# Vootla Chaitanya



speedblaze@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/vootlachaitanya



7899057199



https://github.com/ChaitanyaVootla

# Summary

I'm a Computer Science and Engineering student from NIT Agartala with experience in Vue.js, AngularJs, Nodejs, SQL/PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Canvas and D3.js. Over the course of my career I've created and overhauled features spanning from UI to API to microservices working with multiple teams across multiple time zones.

Currently creating dope UI at JFrog and building JFrog's new CI/CD offering https://jfrog.com/pipelines

# **Experience**



#### Software Developer

**JFrog** 

Apr 2019 - Present (2 years 11 months +)

- Currently building the UI and related backend for Jfrog's new continuous delivery (CD) offering https://jfrog.com/pipelines
- Worked extensively on real-time data visualization using d3js and canvas, client and server side performance optimization
- Worked closely with multiple teams across 3 time-zones on recognizing customer commitments, product design and UX

Current stack: Javascript, Vue.js, Nodejs, postgres, Jest and cypress (for tests)

# Software Developer

Shippable

Jun 2016 - Mar 2019 (2 years 10 months)

- Part of the team that built the most versatile CI/CD platform(Shippable), created and overhauled features spanning from UI to API to microservices
- Owned and created many features like historic insights, graph visualization, worked closely with product team to flesh out and fine tune features
- Worked with the company until it successfully got acquired by the market leader (JFrog)

Stack: Javascript, Angularis, Nodeis, MongoDB, Postgres



#### Intern

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur

May 2015 - Jul 2015 (3 months)

Completed an unfinished project in which ultrasound is used to recognize gestures using signal analysis and machine learning in mobile devices.

#### Education



**National Institute of Technology Agartala** 

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science And Engineering

2012 - 2016 7.38 CGPA (6th semester)

Nava Bharat Public School

2001 - 2009 87.7% (CBSE board)

### **Licenses & Certifications**

- NTPEL course on programming , algorithms and data structures NPTEL
- NTPEL course on introduction to c NPTEL
- DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Specialization Coursera 3MP7PXK3YVH6
- TensorFlow: Advanced Techniques Specialization Coursera CTWUCLAZDZPP

## **Skills**

Node.js • AngularJS • PostgreSQL • Android Development • Docker • PHP • C • MongoDB • C++ • Java

#### **Honors & Awards**

National 39th rank in NPTEL's introduction to programming in c course - NPTEL Feb 2015

Featured in top scorers page in NPTEL's introduction to programming in c course for securing 99% score

link to the page: https://nptel.ac.in/noc/courses/noc14/SEM2/noc14-cs02/